Dennou Boukenki
Plan
Webdiver Production Committee
Original Plan
Ishikawa Hiroto
Series Composition
Sekijima Mayori
Character Design
Takahashi Naruyo
Concept Design
Color Scheme
Moriki Yasuhiro
Kawami Takuya
Production Designer
Director of Audiography
Composite Director
Iwase Eiji
Tanaka Hideyuki
Nagaushi Yutaka
Music
Music Producer
Music Collaboration
Hayashi Yuzo
Kumada Kazuo
Television Tokyo Music
Opening Theme
Lyrics
Composer/Arrangement
Takatori Hideaki
Hirama Akihiko
Song
Columbia Japan
Production Collaboration
Animation Production
Animation Producer
AEON (We've)
Kachihide Yuki
Nomura Hiroshi
Director
Okajima Kunitoshi
Producer
Iwata Makiko (TV Tokyo)
Yamazaki Tatsuji
Chief Director
Negishi Hiroshi
Production
생명을 건 라다의 공격으로 배리어의 효과가 낮아져 버추얼 다이버랜드는 소멸의 위기를 맞았다.
After Lada's all-out attack, barrier has became defective and Virtual Diverland was about to disappear.
Akibat serangan Lada yang mengorbankan jiwanya, efek barier menurun, dan Virtual Diverland perlahan menghilang.
매지컬 스테이션으로의 탈출을 서두르는 아이들의 길을 방해하기 위해 데리트로스 아이가 나타났다.
In front of the children preparing to escape to Magical Station, Deletloss Eye appears to obstruct their path.
Di hadapan anak-anak yang sedang terburu-buru mempersiapkan evakuasi ke Magical Station, Deletloss Eye menghalangi mereka.
켄토는 친구들을 구하기 위해 당연히 힘써줄 13 웹나이트와 함께 데리트로스 아이에 향했다.
To save his friends, Kento headed to Deletloss Eye with 13 Webknights who will do their best.
Untuk menolong teman-temannya, Kento meluncur dan melawan Deletloss Eye bersama dengan ketigabelas Webknight.
통철한 싸움 끝에 결국 빅토리 참으로 데리트로스 아이를 소멸시켰다.
After a battle, they managed to get rid of Deletloss Eye with Victory Slash.
Setelah pertarungan yang sengit, akhirnya Deletloss Eye berhasil dihilangkan dengan Victory Slash.
희망찬 내일!
데리트로스 성을 목표로
Tomorrow of Hope!
Aim for Deletloss Castle
Hari Esok Penuh Harapan! Menuju Deletloss Castle
안 돼... 잠이 안 와...
I can't sleep...
Gawat. Aku tidak bisa tidur...
할아버지에게.
To grandpa.
Untuk Kakek.
결국, 버추얼 다이버랜드가 사라져 버렸습니다.
At last, Virtual Diverland has disappeared.
Akhirnya, Virtual Diverland telah menghilang.
많은 추억과 함께.
Along with lots of memories.
Bersama dengan banyak kenangan.
지금부터 우리는... 우리는...
From now on, we will... will...
Mulai saat ini, kami akan... akan...
카이토! 언제 왔어?
Kaito! Did I woke you up?
Kaito! Dari kapan kau di sini?
아오이, 우리 어떻게 되는 걸까.
Aoi, are we going to be fine?
Aoi, apa yang akan terjadi pada kita?
류토나 데리트로스에 이길 수 있는 걸까.
Can we defeat Ryuto and Deletloss?
Apakah kita bisa mengalahkan Ryuto dan Deletloss?
진짜 다이버랜드에 돌아갈 수 있을까.
Will we be able to return to the real Diverland?
Apa kita bisa kembali ke Diverland yang sesungguhnya?
카이토.
Kaito.
괜찮아. 꼭 돌아갈 수 있을 거야.
It's all right. We'll go back at last.
Tenang saja. Kita pasti bisa pulang.
-정말?
-응. 기억해 봐, 카이토.
-Really?
-Yes. Let me jog your memory.
-Benarkah?
-Sungguh. Coba kau ingat-ingat, Kaito.
우리는 데리트로스에게 마음뿐만이 아니라 몸까지 데리트로스 게이트에 강제전송되어 버추얼 다이버랜드에 왔잖아.
We were transferred forcefully by Deletloss. Not only our minds but also our bodies had arrived to Virtual Diverland.
Kita dipindah secara paksa oleh Deletloss. Tidak hanya jiwa kita, tapi badan kita juga ikut dipindahkan ke Virtual Diverland.
처음 본 버추얼 다이버랜드는 폐허였을 뿐이야.
Virtual Diverland that we saw was a mess at first.
Virtual Diverland yang kita lihat saat itu hanya tersisa puing-puing bangunan saja.
전기도 수도도 가스도 화장실도 병원도 없지. 가족도 친구도 없는 세계.
No electricity, no waterworks, no gas, no toilet, and no hospital. The world without family nor friends.
Tidak ada listrik, air, gas, minimarket dan juga rumah sakit. Dunia tanpa keluarga dan teman kita.
그래도 우린 힘을 합해 어떻게든 살아 왔잖아.
But we somehow managed to keep living on.
Tapi, dengan menyatukan kekuatan, bukankah kita berhasil bertahan hidup?
즐거웠던 일만 있던 것도 아니야. 슬픈 일도 있었어.
It's not like we were happy all the time. There were sad happenings too.
Selain saat-saat bahagia, ada juga saat-saat susah.
우리 모두 힘 내서 잘 해 왔잖아. 모두가 함께한다면 할 수 없는 일은 없어!
We kept doing a good job together. If we all do together, there's nothing we can't do!
Kita semua selalu berusaha, kan? Kalau kita menyatukan kekuatan, kita bisa melakukan apapun!
응...
Maybe...
Iya...
카이토, 그런 표정을 지으면 친구가 널 보고 웃을 거야! 봐봐!
Kaito, if you make that face, your friend might laugh at you! Look!
Kaito, kalau raut mukamu seperti itu, nanti ditertawakan temanmu, loh! Lihat, deh!
크로루...
Kuroru...
크로루도 우리를 응원해주고 있어.
Even Kuroru are cheering for us.
Kuroru pun selalu mendukung kita.
근데 저 류토에게 이길 수 있을까, 우리?
But can we defeat Ryuto?
Tapi, apa kita bisa mengalahkan Ryuto?
류토.
Ryuto.
모든 준비는 끝났다.
All preparations are done.
Semua persiapannya sudah selesai.
곧 최강의 힘을 손에 넣을 때가 왔다.
It's finally time to have and use the ultimate power.
Akhirnya tibalah waktu dimana aku mendapatkan kekuatan yang terkuat.
처음 봤을 때부터 이렇게 재미있을 거라고 생각했지, 켄토.
Ever since I know you for the first time, I thought it would be fun, Kento.
Sejak kita pertama kali bertemu, kau sudah banyak menghiburku, Kento.
당연하다. 이 류토는 유우키 켄토의 전투 데이터를 토대로 태어난 최강의 웹다이버기 때문이지.
Of course. I, Ryuto, is the strongest Webdiver made based on the data from battles against Yuuki Kento.
Tentu saja. Aku adalah Webdiver terkuat yang diciptakan berdasarkan data pertarungan Yuuki Kento.
그런데 어째서. 대체 왜 나는 켄토에게 이길 수 없는 것인가?
But why. Why can't I defeat Kento?
Namun begitu, mengapa aku tidak bisa mengalahkannya?
Brought to you by Subdiver
확실히 류토는 강해. 켄토보다 강할 지도 모르지.
Yes, Ryuto is strong. Maybe stronger than Kento.
Ya, Ryuto memang kuat. Mungkin lebih kuat daripada Kento.
응.
Right.
Iya.
그래도 켄토는 포기하지 않았어. 강해지기 위해 목숨을 걸고 훈련을 했잖아!
But Kento didn't give up. Kento trained really hard to become stronger!
Tapi, Kento tidak menyerah. Kento berlatih sekeras mungkin untuk jadi lebih kuat, kan?
그래. 훈련을 받은 켄토의 성장은 내 예상보다 빨랐다.
Right. After the training, Kento's growth was faster than I expected.
Benar. Berkat latihannya, Kento tumbuh jauh lebih cepat dari dugaanku.
켄토는 계속 성장을 거듭해 나의 종 라다까지도.
Kento kept growing up, and finally my slave Lada has been also...
Kento terus tumbuh, dan pelayanku, Lada pun, juga...
그래. 켄토 혼자만의 힘이 아니야. 모두가 힘을 모아 류토나 데리트로스 몬스터를 이긴 거야!
That's right. It's not Kento's power which only did it. We all defeated Ryuto and Deletloss Monster only after combing our powers!
Itu benar. Tidak bisa hanya dengan kekuatan Kento saja. Kita semua mengalahkan Ryuto dan Deletloss Monster dengan menyatukan kekuatan!
웹체인지! 드라그온, 어택 모드!
Webchange! Dragwon, Attack Mode!
글라디온, 캐논 모드!
Gladion, Cannon Mode!
슈퍼 블랙 홀 캐논!
Super Black Hole Cannon!
웹체인지! 다이탈리온, 어택 모드!
Webchange! Ditalion, Attack Mode!
글라디온, 노바 모드!
Gladion, Nova Mode!
슈퍼 액스 노바!
Super Axe Nova!
그래! 나도 형이나 글라디온하고 힘을 합쳐 함께 싸워왔던 거네!
I see! So I was already fighting along with my brother and Gladion!
Benar juga! Akupun juga telah bertarung bersama Kakak dan Gladion!
맞아! 지금부터의 싸움도 모두가 힘을 합친다면 류토에게도 데리트로스 몬스터에게도 지지 않을 거야. 꼭 이길 거야!
Good! If we combine forces for the upcoming battles, we won't lose to neither Ryuto nor Deletloss Monster. We'll be victorious!
Iya! Kalau kita tetap menyatukan kekuatan, kita tidak akan kalah melawan Ryuto ataupun Deletloss Monster. Kita pasti menang!
응, 응! 꼭 이길 거야!
Yeah, right! We'll win!
Iya! Kita pasti menang, ya!
말 잘 했어, 카이토!
Good to hear that from you, Kaito!
Semangat yang bagus, Kaito!
형! 모두!
Brother! Everybody!
Kakak! Semuanya!
반드시 원래 다이버랜드에 돌아가자. 우리 모두의 힘을 합쳐서!
Let's go back to the real Diverland. Let's combine forces!
Mari kita pulang ke Diverland yang dulu dengan menyatukan kekuatan kita!
가자! 류토가 기다리고 있을 데리트로스 성에!
Let's go! To the Deletloss Castle where Ryuto will be waiting at!
Ayo pergi! Ke Deletloss Castle dimana Ryuto menunggu!
그래!
Good!
Ayo!
슬슬 오는군, 켄토. 허나 곧 글라디온의 데이터는 전부 손에 넣게 되어 있지.
You're coming after all, Kento. But Gladion's data is destined to be mine at last.
Akhirnya kau datang juga, Kento. Tapi, semua data Gladion sudah ada di tanganku.
Screenplay
Maeyamada Ken'ichi
Storyboarding
Staging
Okajima Kunitoshi
Ishida Hiroshi
Voice Actor
Yuuki Kento
Gladion
Arisugawa Aoi
Asaba Naoki
Takeuchi Junko
Kobayashi Yumiko
Sugita Tomokazu
Kikuchi Shiho
Kurachi Shou
Kaida Yuki
Voice Actor
Jean J. Jekyll
Nakai Masataka
Yuuki Kaito
Takagi Reiko
Kuroru
Naruse Makoto
Ryuto
Yoshino Hiroyuki
Lada
Nakamura Yuuichi
Voice Actor
Jaguaron
Kawashima Tokuyoshi
Phoenixon
Suzumura Ken'ichi
Kerberion
Miyashita Michio
Orthorion
Suyama Akio
Garyun
Konishi Katsuyuki
Dragwon
Kawada Shinji
Deletloss
Tobita Nobuo
Ending Theme
Lyrics
Oikawa Neko
Composer
Suzuki Kisaburo
Arranger
Kouno Yougo
Singer
Kageyama Hironobu
Insert Song
Lyrics
Arranger
Kyouda Seiichi
Singer
Columbia Japan
Production Cooperation
Animation Production
AEON (We've)
Subtitle
Subdiver
ファン字幕
サブダイバー
Production
Thank you for watching!
다음 이야기 미리보기
Preview for Next Episode
Episode Selanjutnya
최후의 결전을 향한 우리 앞에 미궁의 데리트로스 게이트가 앞길을 가로막아.
While we were heading for the final battle, labyrinth Deletloss Gate is in our way.
Di saat menuju ke pertarungan terakhir, labirin pada Deletloss Gate menghalangi jalan kami.
여기서 뚫고 지나가지 않으면 류토가 있는 곳에는 절대 닿지 못할 거야!
If we don't make it through, we won't make it to the Ryuto's place!
Kalau kita tidak melewatinya, kita tidak akan sampai ke tempat Ryuto!
엔제, 지금이야말로 힘을 빌려줄 때야!
Enge, now is the time that you need to lend your power!
Enge, ini saatnya kau pinjamkan kekuatanmu pada kami!
매지컬 스테이션, 발진이야!
Magical Station, dispatch!
Magical Station, meluncur!
전뇌모험기 웹다이버의 다음 이야기!
Next episode of Dennou Boukenki Webdiver!
Di episode Dennou Boukenki Webdiver selanjutnya!
Thanks for watching! - Subdiver
See you at http://subdiver.soreepeong.com/ !